

ABOUT

Hey, I'm Ryan and I work with marketing stacks.

My specialties include automation, administration, operations, reporting, development/coding, UI/UX personalization, APIs and webhooks -- and if you name a CRM platform, I've probably worked with it in my 8 years of marketing experience.

CONTACT

954.235.0191 blackjosephryan@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/blackjosephryan www.ryanjblack.io

EDUCATION

University of Florida M.A. in Mass Communications Web Design & Online Communication Dec 2018

> University of South Florida B.A. in Mass Communications Concentration in Journalism May 2015

SKILLS

CRM Admin

Salesforce, Pardot, Active Campaign, Moosend, HubSpot (Certified), Marketo, Zapier, Klaviyo, Infusionsoft, SMS

Adobe CC + Content Creation

WordPress Admin

PHP, eCommerce, Multisite, SQL, MAMP

Email Deliverability

Kickbox, Validity, Litmus, CAN-SPAM, GDPR, CASL

SEO + SEM

Yoast, aHrefs, Raven Tools, SEMRush, SpyFu, Google Analytics (Certified), Bing Analytics, Performance Optimization

Social Media Marketing

Facebook Ads, YouTube, Twitter, LinkedIn Campaign Manager, Instagram, Google My Business

Codina

HTML5, CSS3, JS/jQuery, React, NextJS Atom Git/Github

EXPERIENCE

Email Marketing Specialist | 2021 - Current

PPK I Tampa, FL

- + Director and strategist of all agency client email and automated marketing efforts
- + Work directly with client marketing stacks, including CRM onboarding, auditing, SMS, UX/UI and deliverability.
- + Brands include Wonder Bread, PDQ, Glory Days, Pinch-A-Penny, Florida Lotto, GTE, Tastykake, Tires Plus, Florida Aquarium
- + Recent top performing campaign ROI: \$1.2 million.

Inbound Marketing Strategist | 2020 - 2021

Bluleadz | Tampa, FL

- + Provided ongoing marketing support for dozens of clients, increasing traffic, contacts and customers for B2B, SaaS and tech companies.
- + Average client increased traffic 10% month over month, 4-6% revenue QoQ for top clients and reduced ad spend by an average of 25% while maintaining clicks and improving conversions. Database cleaning and opt-in campaigns.

Internet Marketing Strategist | 2020

Marketing Specialist | 2019

Trucks & Parts (et al.) | Tampa, FL

- + Led web marketing initiatives for all company banners/verticals and locations, including coordination between teams for: CRM, web design, API integrations, SEO reporting, automated email campaigns, lead segmentation and lead assignment.
- + Decreased site main bounce rate from 95% to 55%, increased website CTR by 3% month-to-month while reducing the legacy CPC budget by 50%.
- + Led a UF Student Research Group through website audit and redesign.

Internet Marketing Specialist | 2018 – 2019

Club Z! Tutoring (et al.) | Tampa, FL

- + Site creation and multisite admin for over 600+ franchise locations worldwide, including SEO audits and research for each location.
- + Improved new franchisee page conversions by 15% month-to-month, improved page rankings - most to page 1 on Google within 45 days.
- + Content creation for virtual learning sites, including SEO web copy and comprehensive email workflows.

Content Marketing Assistant | 2018

University of Florida CJC | Gainesville, FL

+ Created spotlight content for SEO visibility showcasing the students and teachers of the University of Florida CJC Graduate Education program

SEO Copywriter & Editor | 2016 – 2018

LawnPartsPro.com (Power Mower Sales) | Miami, FL (Remote)

- + Content creation including SEO web copy and customer engagement.
- + WordPress administration duties including template design.
- + Marketing email copy for sales promotions (Constant Contact).

Marketing Specialist | 2015

Marketing Intern | 2015

Ultra Clean Systems, Inc. | Oldsmar, FL

- + Designed, wrote, and edited operator and technical manuals.
- + WordPress admin

PERSONAL CLIENT WEBSITES

Tampa Crane and Body | 2020 Tampa Bay Watch | 2018 RAMMP Restaurant Group | 2018